# Siddhartha Danthuluri

E-mail: siddharth@sidtri.com § Website: <a href="http://sidtri.com">http://sidtri.com</a> § Phone: (+91) 9632389771 Hyderabad

# **OBJECTIVE**

During past **4.0 years** I've been working as a full stack software developer specialized in Ruby on Rails. I'm passionate about learning new technologies that broaden my scope on programming.

I develop web applications that become more effective. I consider my interest more working on **refactoring** spaghetti code.

My development engagements include Frontend Designing include **Sass and BEM** Methodologies, Developing **micro services**, deploying websites on **cloud hosting** using Amazon AWS and Docker.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Happ Tech Pvt Ltd

November 2016 — Present

Software Engineer

Works:

- Happ Core Product (Roaster) Design an interface for doctors to schedule their timetable and assign slots based on the timings using recursive pattern for patients to book appointments. (Implemented from scratch and live at https://happ.co.in doctors dashboard)
- Happ Roaster sync up with mobile Using amazon SQS and SNS provided sync up between mobile apps and provided API for all services

## DispatchTrack Software Pvt Ltd

June 2016 — October 2016

Senior Software Developer

Works:

- DispatchTrack Products: Re-Developed old obsolute codebase to new using angular 2 along with ruby api behind. ( https://dtidev.dispatchtrack.com )
- Maintain core product ( https://dtdev.dispatchtrack.com )
- Managed cloud platform for Dispatchtrack Intermodal ( https://dtidev.dispatchtrack.com ). Handled usecase to handle high impact, metrics and error handling .

## Mahaswami Technologies Pvt Ltd

Sep 2015 — May 2016

Senior Software Developer

Works:

- Scholar Base for students around 10 lack ( http://cgscholar.com ) [ Analyse and made performance optimisations, Handled high throughput, Refactor and solve common bug fixes ]
- Card Game for IOS (Ruby Motion)
- Firefighter Calculator http://www.a2app.com/firefightercalculator
- Career Search http://www.a2app.com/careersearch/
- Salary Search http://www.a2app.com/salarysearch/

Siddhartha Danthuluri

- Fido Seek (Yet to be deployed)
- Potus ( Presidents of united states ) Yet to be deployed

## Stunapp Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

March 2015 — August 2015

Core Software Developer

List of websites as a single core developer designed, developed and deployed

• FitnessPapa ( https://fitnesspapa.com )

https://yourstory.com/2015/07/fitnesspapa/

Platform for all fitness related services available through this platform and has an advantage of choosing fitness services from wide range without paying extra charges and can choose multiple at once.

( React, Amazon web services including EC2-S3-SQS-Autoscaling-Load Balancers, Redis, CronJobs, Sass, Rails )

Houzome ( http://houzome.com )

A marketplace where we put together designers, craftsmen, interior services vendors as well as sellers of specialty furniture and appliances. (E-Commerce)

Stack: Ruby on Rails, React, Amazon web services, Sass

Note: Design changed now and is now handled by other vendors

- StunApp ( https://stunapp.com )
  Company website designed carefully that fits modern world standards
- NetworkG ( http://networkg.in )

#### Media3 International Pvt. Ltd

May 2014 — Feb 2015

Technical Lead

List of websites as a single core developer handled to (Get the project, Design, Develop, Deploy, Maintain)

- http://talenteconomics.com
  Build to completely optimise entire website through CMS, Benchmark assessments, Customized dynamic report generators, Blog, plus designed roles for practitioners and Certified talent economers.
  Stack: Ruby on Rails, Refinery CMS, Bootstrap with sass, SEO Friendly.
- http://resalemillionairebook.com

Status: Inactive

Website related to launch a book called Resale millionaire which includes gift cards, coupons, Referral. Stack: Ruby on Rails, Bootstrap, CronJobs.

http://michaelclarkeacademy.com/

Designed high standards front-end that fits the modern world.

Stack: Front-end using sass and compass.

List of websites with contributors.

http://www.pomefresh.com/
 Stack: Ruby on Rails

• http://www.sumasika.com/ ( Money Transfer website )

Siddhartha Danthuluri 2

Status: inactive

Ref: https://angel.co/sumasika-money-transfer/jobs

Platform to transfer money to Ghana from all around the world with less charges.

Designed a simple, intuitive front-end with dashboard to transfer money securely.

Stack: Ruby on Rails, Front-end using foundation framework, Payment gateway integration (stripe, paypal)

http://mbanumbers.com/ ( Social Network )
 Stack: Ruby on Rails

Build web-based applications in Ruby on Rails for clients remotely all around from different origins including information services, Retail, Healthcare, Sports, Professional services, and Education.

## **Bluefrog Technologies**

June 2013 — May 2014

Software Developer

Developed custom Dynamic websites for a customers that deals with services belonging to government tasks.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### Experience with

- Ruby, Rails
- IOS Development using RubyMotion
- Cloud Deployment (Amazon web services Associate Developer), Docker
- Redis
- Mysql / Postgresql
- HAML, React, Sass, Susy Framework
- API development- SEO, Page speed, webmaster tools

## **EDUCATION**

## **Bachelor of Electronics**

September 2009 — May 2013

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University

Intermediate

July 2007 — may 2009

Sri Chaitanya

### REFERENCES

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/siddhartha-danthuluri

Github: https://github.com/sidtri

YourStory: https://yourstory.com/2015/07/fitnesspapa/

Personal website: http://sidtri.com

Siddhartha Danthuluri 3